# DANIEL ABBOTT FULL STACK DEVELOPER

#### ■ danielabbott@daniel-abbott.com

- www.daniel-abbott.com
- **\** 3852165115
- Magna, UT
- in daniel-abbott-dev
- O daniel-abbott

#### Skills

#### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

**JavaScript** 

HTML

CSS

React

Redux

Node.js

**Express** 

**REST** 

GraphQL

SQLite

PostgreSQL

Django

Mocha

Chai

Jest

LESS

Webpack

Deployment

Continuous Integration

## **Education**

## Lambda School

Jan. 2018 to June 2018

- 6+ month Computer Science & Software Engineering Academy
- Immersive hands-on curriculum with a focus on computer science, software engineering, and web development.
- Course work: HTML/CSS/JS, React, Redux, Node, Express, MongoDB, Python, Django, SQL, C.
- Hands-on experience with client and server testing.

### **About Me**

I am a full-stack developer who enjoys learning new technologies and building solutions. I am experienced with technologies like HTML5/CSS3/JS, React, Redux, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Python, Django and SQL. I am also experienced with test-driven development (Jest, Mocha, Chai), Agile methodology, Git workflow, deployment, and continuous integration. Additionally, I'm interested in game and software development, both in using existing solutions such as Unreal Engine 4 and Godot, as well as lower-level frameworks and languages such as SDL and C/C++. Lastly, I possess strong technical troubleshooting and communication skills.

## **Projects**

#### Ouizzer

Sept. 2018 to Oct. 2018

- A simple web application for teachers to create quizzes and distribute them quickly to students via email.
- This app uses React for front-end user interaction, Django on the backend, PostgreSQL for the database, and GraphQL for the majority of API calls.
- Implements continuous integration through Codeship to allow automatic testing and deployment to Heroku.
- Building this project involved learning to use GraphQL queries and mutations, as well as researching and implementing existing libraries (Apollo Client and Graphene) to make best use of GraphQL.

## ShooterGameProject

May 2018 to Current

- Top down, 2D twin-stick shooter, being built in the Godot engine using the built-in GDScript language (similar to Python).
- Implements lighting and shadowmapping to accentuate levels, as well as provide a line-of-sight visualization system.
- Primarily serves as a project to learn the fundamentals of game design and development.

# **Employment**

## Lambda School

Remote

**Teaching Assistant** 

• Three-month contract position managing groups of between 8 - 24 students

- Assisted students with assignment questions and technical issues.
- · Led stand-up meetings.
- Led individual one-on-one discussions.
- Reviewed pull requests.

#### **NetflixCS**

Salt Lake City, UT May 2015 to Dec. 2017

July 2018 to Sept. 2018

Tier Two Technical Escalations

- Took technical escalation calls from customer service sites around the world.
- Investigated streaming and billing issues, and measured impact to the customer as well as the product.
- Performed in-depth investigations and documented all findings and troubleshooting steps attempted in JIRA issue tracking software.